(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-07T22:41:48.123577",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
走りなさい 早く
Run, run fast,
もっと 早く
even faster,
哀しみに追いつかれないように
so that sorrow won't catch up to you.
探しなさい 明かりの灯る道を
Search for the path where the lights are lit;
それは それは 眩しいでしょう
it will surely be dazzlingly bright.
挑みなさい 君の美しさや
Defy anything that tries
尊さを傷つけるモノに
to harm your beauty and preciousness.
眠りなさい 疲れたら眠りなさい
Go to sleep; if you grow weary, just sleep,
神話を持たないあの星座のように
just like that constellation without a myth.
手を離した後 君は気づくだろう
After letting go of my hand, you will realize;
指の形 体温
the shape of my fingers, my warmth,
その名残が胸を刺す
those lingering traces will pierce your heart.
忘れたことも忘れてしまえ
Forget that you even forgot,
哀しみも温もりも消えてしまえ
let all the sorrow and warmth vanish away.
されど今も耳に残るは
Yet what still echoes in my ears even now
固く再会を願うような
is like a solemn wish to meet again...
さよなら
Goodbye...
アデュー　アデュー
Adieu, adieu...
ラブ・ユー　アンド・ユー
Love you and you...
踊りなさい
Dance,
誰に笑われても
even if everyone laughs at you.
泡雪を払う
Brushing away the light snow,
枝のように
like branches.
叫びなさい
Scream,
心から叫びなさい
scream straight from your heart.
ここに確かにいたんだと
Let it echo
響かせて
that you were truly here.
行き合いの空に
In the sky of changing seasons,
遠花火が滲む
distant fireworks blur.
帰るべき家を探す永い
Searching for a home to return to,
長い旅路を
along this long, long journey,
行くなら
if you are to go on.
高鳴らせ その心臓を
Let that heartbeat race,
最後の一撃まで
until the very last beat,
君のものだ
it belongs to you.
涙 涙 溢れるがいい
Let your tears, your tears overflow.
この一滴が 君の街を育ててるだろう
For this single droplet will surely nurture your town.
それは千年の ホームシックでした
It was a millennium of homesickness.
無限さえも 数え終えて
Having finished counting even infinity.
怪物のような
Like a monster,
世界を呑み込んで
swallowing up the world.
戦い続ける人と
For those who keep fighting,
君は エールを エールを
you send cheers, send cheers.
旅は続く
The journey continues.
忘れたことも 忘れてしまえ
Forget even the things you've forgotten.
悲しみも温もりも 消えちまえ
Let both sorrow and warmth vanish away.
今も今も今も 君色を乞うわ
Even now, even now, even now, I beg for your colors.
固く咲いた体温 願うような
As if praying for the firmly blossomed warmth,
さよなら
goodbye.
アデュー アデュー
Adieu, adieu.
ラブ・ユー アンド・ユー
Love you and you.
アデュー アデュー
Adieu, adieu.
Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah
駄目駄目駄目 脳みその中から
No, no, no, from within my brain,
「やめろ馬鹿」と喚くモラリティ
morality screams, "Stop it, idiot!"
ダーリン ベイビー ダーリン 半端なくラブ
Darling, baby, darling, an insane love!
ときめき浮き足立つフィロソフィー
A heart-throbbing, restless philosophy.
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
A deadly adorable upward glance,
なにがし法に触れるくらい
close to breaking some kind of law.
ばら撒く乱心 気づけば蕩尽
Scattering madness, squandered before I know it,
この世に生まれた君が悪い
you're to blame for being born into this world.
やたらとしんどい恋煩い
An overwhelmingly painful lovesickness,
バラバラなる頭とこの身体
my head and this body falling apart.
頸動脈からアイラブユーが噴き出て
"I love you" gushes from my carotid artery,
アイリスアウト
Iris out.
一体どうしよう この想いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What to do with these feelings?
あばらの奥を ザラメが溶けて ゲロになりそう
Deep in my ribs, brown sugar melts, making me wanna vomit.
瞳孔バチ開いて 溺れ死にそう
Pupils wide open, I feel like drowning.
今 この世で君だけ大正解
Right now, in this world, you alone are absolute perfection.
ダーリン ダーリン
Darling, darling,
darling, darling.
ダーリン ダーリン
Darling, darling,
darling, darling.
ひっくり返っても勝ちようない
Even upside down, there's no way to win,
君だけルールは適用外
the rules don't apply only to you.
四つともオセロは黒しかない カツアゲ放題
All four Othello corners are black, extortion with no limit.
君が笑顔で放ったアバダケダブラ
That Avada Kedavra you cast with a smile,
デコにスティグマ 申し訳ねえな
left a stigma on my forehead, so sorry about that.
矢を刺して 貫いて ここ弱点
Shoot an arrow, pierce right through, this is my weak spot.
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
A deadly adorable upward glance,
なにがし法に触れるくらい
close to breaking some kind of law.
ばら撒く乱心 気づけば蕩尽
Scattering madness, squandered before I know it,
この世に生まれた君が悪い
you're to blame for being born into this world.
パチモンでもいい 何でもいい
Even a knockoff is fine, anything is fine,
今君と名付いてる全て欲しい
I want everything bearing your name right now.
頸動脈からアイラブユーが噴き出て
"I love you" gushes from my carotid artery,
アイリスアウト
Iris out.
一体どうしよう この想いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What to do with these feelings?
あばらの奥を ザラメが溶けて ゲロになりそう
Deep in my ribs, brown sugar melts, making me wanna vomit.
瞳孔バチ開いて 溺れ死にそう
Pupils wide open, I feel like drowning.
今 この世で君だけ...
Right now, in this world, you alone...
限界世界
A world at its limit
Darling Darling Darling Darling Darling Darling Darling Darling!
永遠の意味知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It's time to show the answer to you, who knows not the meaning of eternity
夢幻に続く螺旋の先へ
To the end of the spiral leading to infinity
夢幻
[Song: Mugen]
言い訳に聞こえた理由は 儚い未来手繰った弱さ
The reason it sounded like an excuse was the weakness of clinging to a fleeting future,
それを強さとはき違えている
mistaking that for strength.
憎い 憎い 醜い 醜い
Hateful, hateful, hideous, hideous,
月を隠すほどの
so dark as to hide the moon.
黒く 黒く 淀む 心
A black, black, stagnant heart,
君さえ居なければ
if only you weren't here.
揺らいでる 揺らいでいる
Swaying, swaying,
花のように意思をつなぐ
connecting our wills like flowers.
奪っていく 奪っていく
Tearing away, tearing away,
嵐のように心を裂く
ripping hearts apart like a storm.
永遠の意味知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It's time to show the answer to you, who knows not the meaning of eternity.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先に
At the end of the spiral leading to infinity,
待つのは誰
who is waiting?
生まれ落ちた定めを呑んだ 背負った数の名前を覚えた
Swallowed the fate I was born into, remembered the names of all those I bore.
爛れるほど心燃やす感情
Emotions burning my heart to the point of festering.
憎い 憎い 醜い 醜い
Hateful, hateful, hideous, hideous,
世界を分かつほどの
enough to split the world apart.
怒り 怒り 燃やす 心
Rage, rage, a burning heart,
君さえ居なければ
if only you weren't here.
揺らいでる 揺らいでいる
Swaying, swaying,
花のように意思をつなぐ
connecting our wills like flowers.
奪っていく 奪っていく
Tearing away, tearing away,
嵐のように心を裂く
ripping hearts apart like a storm.
永遠の意味知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It's time to show the answer to you, who knows not the meaning of eternity.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先で
At the end of the spiral leading to infinity...
鬼哭に耳を傾けた仕舞いよ
Listening to the wailing demons, this is the end.
この身に宿る万物で終いよ
It ends with everything dwelling within me.
夢幻を他者に託した弱き人
The weak who entrusted their dreams to others...
命の輝きは幾星霜に
The brilliance of life across countless years,
祈りの瞬きが照らす斜陽に
in the setting sun lit by a flicker of prayer.
千夜を身に宿し
Bearing a thousand nights within,
解を押し付けろ
force the answer upon them.
枯らしていく 枯らしていく
Withering away, withering away,
夢幻の夜に花を裂く
tearing the flower apart in the night of illusions.
繋いでいく 繋いでいく
Binding together, connecting along,
嵐に種を播いていく
sowing seeds into the storm.
揺らいでる 揺らいでいる
Swaying, swaying,
花のように意思をつなぐ
connecting our wills like flowers.
奪っていく 奪っていく
Tearing away, tearing away,
嵐のように心を裂く
ripping hearts apart like a storm.
永遠の意味知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It's time to show the answer to you, who knows not the meaning of eternity.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先で
At the end of the spiral leading to infinity,
待つのは誰
who is waiting?
イエーーイ！
Yeah!
はい！ということで、NIKOに来ていただきましたー！
Alright! And so, we have NIKO here with us!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！NIKOちゃんです！
Happy birthday! It's NIKO-chan!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you so much!
よくお前、歌い切れたな！
You did amazing singing through all that!
なんかもうね、顔…顔はもう…
Like, your face... your face is already...
涙…涙で滲んでいるw
blurred with... blurred with tears, haha!
大丈夫かって？
Are you okay?
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much!
いやいやいや、ありがとうございます、こちらこそ。
No, no, no, thank you as well!
ということで、2026年の生誕祭はですね、
And so, for my 2026 birthday live...
あのー、ニコさんが生出演ということで
Niko-san made a live guest appearance!
はい！
Yes!
あの、ニコたんもね、3Dになったということで、
Since Niko-tan got her 3D model as well,
なりました！
I did!
はい！
Yes!
で、ニコたんが「いつかルイ先輩の隣で歌いたい」って言ってくれてたんで、
and Niko-tan had told me, "I want to sing by Lui-senpai's side someday,"
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
なので今日は、お呼びさせていただきました！
so today, I invited her here!
ありがとうございます！本当に！
Thank you so much, really!
いやー、めちゃくちゃかっこいい曲を歌わせていただきましたが、皆さんいかがでしたかー？
We got to perform such an awesome song together! How did everyone like it?
「ニコたん良かったね」って！
"Niko-tan was great," they say!
いやもう、ニコたんのことはいいんですって！
No, enough about Niko-tan already!
「ニコたん良かったね」って。
"Niko-tan was great!"
そんなことよりですよ、ルイ先輩！ニコたんなんかより、今日重大告知もあるし…
More importantly, Lui-senpai! Forget about me, today you have a major announcement and...
そうなんです。
That's right.
し、新衣装も…
N-New outfit too...
新衣装もあるんです！
There's a new outfit too!
出るんでしたっけ？
You're revealing it, right?
これね、たくさんね、ここのハッシュタグ「鷹嶺ルイ超重大生誕LIVE」ってありますんで、
Yes! We have this hashtag on screen, "#TakaneLuiSuperMajorBirthdayLIVE,"
それでたくさんたくさん、もうポストしてくれたら嬉しいなと思うんですけど、
so I'd be so happy if you could post a lot using it.
今日はたくさん告知もありますし、
We have plenty of announcements today,
そうですよねー！
That's true!
いや、重大告知のもうデッカさも気になるんですけど、
I'm curious about the massive announcements of course,
新衣装がやっぱね、気になる！
but I'm really curious about the new outfit!
やっぱルイ先輩といえば、ちょっとダークネスな感じなのかなーとか思ったり。
When I think of Lui-senpai, I wonder if it's going to be a bit dark...
黒系なのかなーみたいな。
like black-themed or something.
あー、なるほどなるほどなるほど。そう思いますよね。
Ah, I see, I see, I see. You'd think so, right?
はい。
Yes.
ま、それもあります！
Well, there's that too!
えぇっ！？ それも？
Eh?! That too?
はい。
Yes.
ということは？
Which means...?
最初ね、あの固定でも書かせていただいたんですけど、
As I wrote in the pinned comment earlier,
新衣装は最初サブカラーで、
the new outfit starts with a sub-color,
ちょっと清楚な感じの衣装になっております。
and it's a bit of a pure, elegant-styled outfit.
え！？ それもある…？ ここ、ここにもあるって…
What?! There's that too...? You mean here too...?
はい、めちゃくちゃ大量に差分を用意しておりますので、
Yes, we've prepared a massive amount of variations,
最後までね、楽し…
so until the very end, pleas--
なんかすごい騒いでる。
She's getting super hyper.
おかしいよ！差分が！
That's crazy! All those variations!
もういいや。今日は来てくれてありがとう！
Whatever! Thanks for coming today!
あ、わかりました！私、楽屋で応援してます！それでは…
Ah, got it! I'll be cheering you on from the dressing room! Well then...
あ、違います違います！そちらあの、舞踏会会場なんで。
Ah, no no no! Over there is the ballroom venue.
だ、ダメなんですか、ニコたんは？
I-Is Niko-tan not allowed?
はい、ニコたんは呼んでない。招待状もらってないでしょ？
Right, Niko-tan isn't invited. You didn't get an invitation, did you?
もらってないけど！
I didn't, but...!
うん。じゃあ、あのすいませんが楽屋の方にあちらから…
Yeah. So sorry, but the dressing room is that way...
なんでだよー！
Whyyy?!
はい、スタッフさんお願いします。
Staff, please take care of her.
ルイ先輩、お立ち止まりいただきありがとうございます。
Lui-senpai, thank you for stopping by!
ありがと、ありがと。ありがと… 悪質やな。
Thanks, thanks, thanks... You're relentless.
頑張ってください！
Do your best!
ありがと、ありがとね！ありがとねー！
Thank you, thank you! Thanks!
ということでニコたんに来ていただきました。
And that was Niko-tan joining us!
はい、新衣装もね、たくさん見せていきますので、最後まで楽しんでいただけたらなと思います。
Yes, I'll be showing lots of the new outfit, so I hope you enjoy until the very end!
楽屋のニコたんも楽しんでくださいねー！
Niko-tan in the dressing room, have fun too!
それでは聞いてください。『ZIG-ZAG』。
Now then, please listen to: "ZIG-ZAG."
One, two, three, four
ZIG-ZAG
作詞・作曲・編曲：中村歩 / 吉村隆行
[Song: ZIG-ZAG / Lyrics, Music, Arrangement: Ayumu Nakamura / Takayuki Yoshimura]
幸せって囁いたあとで　ラッタッタラッタ
After whispering about happiness, rat-tat-ta-rat-ta
こびりついて離れわ駄目だ　ラッタッタラッタ
Clinging on and refusing to let go, no good, rat-tat-ta-rat-ta
無味無臭の喪失感が　思い出せないや
A tasteless, odorless sense of loss, I can't even remember
忘れたいから歌った　馬鹿だ　ラッタッタラッタ
I sang because I wanted to forget, what an idiot, rat-tat-ta-rat-ta
怨むことも　憎むことも
Neither resenting nor hating,
賢くない故　出来なかった
I wasn't smart enough to do either.
これが君の結末ならば
If this is your conclusion,
笑ってしまいたい
I just want to laugh it off.
本当？
Really?
嘘、嘘、嘘
Lie, lie, lie...
嘘つき
Liar.
大体 大体 大体な
Mostly, mostly, mostly,
奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
I found myself wishing a little for miracles,
もう嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌
and I hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it!
タッチだ ワン・ツー・イン・ワン・レッツ
Touch, one-two-in-one-lets!
痛い痛い痛いな
It hurts, it hurts, it hurts,
おかしいとこ全部抉り取って
Gouging out all the broken parts,
悪評で結構
Bad reputation is totally fine,
好きに呼んでいいよ
feel free to call me whatever you want.
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです
I just want to say bye-bye to trauma,
です　で、で、で、です
I do, I, I, I, I do!
私、甘え上手になれなかった
I couldn't be good at acting spoiled,
可愛げとかが足りなかった
lacking in charm and cuteness.
幸福かい？
Are you happy?
うるさい、愚弄った？
Shut up, are you mocking me?
過去は過去だと割り切っちゃえば
If I just brush it off as "the past is the past,"
「きっといいことあるさ」とかそれくらい
"I'm sure good things will happen" and all that,
百も承知だ　ラッタッタ
I already know full well, rat-tat-ta!
願うことも　祈ることも
Neither wishing nor praying
許されないから黒く染めた
is permitted, so I dyed it black.
元の色も思い出せない
I can't even remember the original color anymore,
絡んだ運命の
the entangled threads
糸　糸　糸　糸
of fate, thread, thread, thread...
大体 大体 大体な
Mostly, mostly, mostly,
悲劇のヒロイン気取っちゃって
putting on the act of a tragic heroine,
もう嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌
and I hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it!
諦めちゃえば？
Why not just give up?
でも会いたい 会いたい 会いたいな
But I want to see you, want to see you, want to see you,
思考回路が混んがらがっちゃって
My train of thought gets all tangled up,
明日またきっと
Tomorrow, surely once again...
壊すけどいいの
Is it okay if I break it?
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです です で・で・で・です
I want to say bye-bye to my trauma, yes, yes, y-y-y-yes!
夢の中で君と
In my dreams, with you,
手を繋いでいるの
I'm holding hands,
何も知らないあの頃の 二人のままで
just like the two of us back then who knew nothing.
でも解っているよ すぐに覚めてしまうと
But I know that I'll wake up soon,
それならばいっそ 君の手でそっと
so if that's the case, gently with your own hands,
止め刺して
deliver the finishing blow.
ほら 今 今 今！
Come on, now, now, now!
やだ 痛い痛い痛い痛いな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
No, it hurts, hurts, hurts, hurts, hoping just a bit for a miracle.
もう嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌！ タチが悪いわ
No way, no way, no way, no way, no way! My attitude is terrible.
ねえ 辛い lie lie lie 否？ おかしいとこ全部抉り取って
Hey, painful lie, lie, lie, isn't it? Gouge out all the messed up parts.
薄情で結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
Cold-hearted is fine, call me whatever you want.
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです です で・で・で・です
I want to say bye-bye to my trauma, yes, yes, y-y-y-yes!
です です で・で・で・です
Yes, yes, y-y-y-yes!
世界欺く揺るぎない正義
An unwavering justice that deceives the world,
ほどいて真実 この手の中
untangling it, the truth is within my grasp.
アイのシナリオ
[Ai no Scenario]
大胆不敵な影が華麗に踊る
A bold and fearless shadow dances magnificently,
君が隠してる秘密 いつか聞かせてよ
the secret you're hiding, tell me about it someday.
伸ばした手で触れる事は誰もできない
Nobody can reach out and touch it,
君が隠してる世界 僕に見させてよ
the world you're hiding, let me see it.
揺れる難解な心
An intricate, wavering heart,
解き明かして奪うその瞳
unraveling it to captivate those eyes.
不安がって泣いてたって見つけらんないよ
Being anxious and crying won't help you find it.
狙う真実はどこへ消えた
Where did the truth you seek vanish to?
たとえ世界欺く解答だとしても
Even if it's an answer that deceives the world,
「信じて」差し出す掌
"Trust me," I hold out my hand.
決して逃げない 怖くはないから
I'll never run away, because I'm not afraid.
目を開け弱さをかき消すんだ
Open your eyes and banish all weakness!
繰り返される運命に君は気づいてる？
Are you aware of this repeating destiny?
僕が隠してる秘密 いつか聞かせるよ
The secret I'm hiding, I'll tell you someday.
歩み寄る偽りの影 君は知らない
An approaching shadow of deceit, you do not know.
芽生えた記憶は絡む 必然の棘で
Sprouting memories are entwined with inevitable thorns.
守りたい想いで ただ立ち向かって
Driven by the desire to protect, I simply stand up
ほどくその絆
and untangle those bonds.
何度だって助けるって揺るぎはしないよ
I will save you again and again, I will never waver.
隠す真実はどこへ消えた
Where did the hidden truth vanish to?
たとえ世界を敵に回したとしても
Even if we turn the whole world against us,
信じて僕だけ 未来も
believe only in me, and our future too.
決して逃げない 迷いはないから
I'll never run away, because there is no doubt in my mind.
シナリオ壊して抗うんだ
Break the scenario and fight back!
世界を敵に回したとしても
Even if the whole world turns into my enemy,
「信じて」差し出す掌
I'll say \"trust me\" and hold out my hand.
決して離さない
I will never let go,
答えは届いた
the answer has reached me.
結んだ運命
This tied-together fate...
この手の中
is right here in my hands.
繰り返された 答えだとしても
Even if it's an answer that repeats itself...
決して逃げない
I will never run away,
怖くはないから
because there's nothing to be afraid of.
抗うんだ
I'm going to fight back!
何度も 何度も
Again and again, again and again,
走り続けるよ
I'll keep on running!
Wake up! 同心円
Wake up! Concentric circles,
Shift up! 見回して
Shift up! Look around!
Speed up! ハートバイティング U.M.A. NEW WORLD!
Speed up! Heart-biting, U.M.A. NEW WORLD!
Jump up! 頂点へ
Jump up! To the top!
Turn up! 声合わせて
Turn up! Unite our voices!
Dream on! 未来繋いで U.M.A. NEW WORLD!
Dream on! Connecting the future, U.M.A. NEW WORLD!
最高潮コンディション 調子ガンガン研ぎ澄ましてこう
Peak condition, let's sharpen our rhythm!
栄光のチャンピオンコース 虎視眈々と狙ってこう
Let's steadily aim for the glorious champion course!
マイペースに（マイペース！）気合レースに超集中
At my own pace (my pace!), super focused on the spirited race!
駆けるセーブは限界 ハートに引火！ U.M.A. Let's go!
Running without holding back, igniting our hearts! U.M.A. Let's go!
最高潮アンビション 一騎打ちの大勝負
Peak ambition, a head-to-head showdown!
成功のチャンスを 全力出して掴んでこう
Let's give it our all and seize the chance of success!
ハイペースより（ハイペース！）気合レースに猛進中
Faster than high-paced (high pace!), charging straight into the spirited race!
覚悟思いをセット 突っ走ってこう
Setting our determination and feelings, let's sprint forward!
友と二人 競い合った 風の中でも
Even in the wind where I competed alongside my friend,
大きな背中 追いかけてた 雨の中でも
even in the rain where I chased after that great back,
何百何千回と 組み交わされてきた
hundreds and thousands of times we crossed paths.
だからどこまでも遠く どこまでも高く
So farther than anywhere, higher than anywhere,
誰よりも早く 誰よりも強く
faster than anyone, stronger than anyone!
さあ、今！ 駆け出した思いは もう止まらない
Now, right now! The feelings that began to run won't stop anymore,
誰にも渡せないゴールまで 弱気な気持ち蹴飛ばして
until the goal that I won't hand over to anyone, kicking away timid feelings!
幾度倒れようと 立ち上がって 走り抜けて
No matter how many times I fall, I'll stand up and run through!
鳴り出した鼓動は 収まらない 最後まで全身全霊をかけて
The beating heart that started ringing won't settle down, dedicating body and soul to the end!
頂点へと手を伸ばして 限界さえ超えて行け
Reach out a hand to the summit, transcend even the limits!
伝説を追い越して 勝利へ
Overtake the legend and head toward victory!
友と二人 競い合った あの喜びも
That joy of competing with my friend,
大きな背中 追いかけてた あの憧れも
that yearning of chasing after that great back,
何千何万回と 生まれ変わっても
even if reborn thousands and tens of thousands of times,
何度も 何度も
again and again, again and again,
走り続けるよ
I'll keep on running!
駆け出した思いは もう止まらない
The feelings that began to run won't stop anymore,
誰もが夢に見てた 未来まで
all the way to the future everyone dreamed of!
勇気も傷も 今は思い出へと ずっと
Both courage and scars are now memories, forever...
すべてを注いで 行け！
Pouring in everything, go!
さあ、今！ 鳴り出した鼓動は 収まらない
Now, right now! The beating heart that started ringing won't settle down,
最後まで全身全霊をかけて
dedicating body and soul to the very end!
頂点へと手を伸ばして 限界さえ超えて行け
Reach out a hand to the summit, transcend even the limits!
伝説を追い越して 勝利へ
Overtake the legend and head toward victory!
友と二人 競い合った あの喜びも
That joy of competing with my friend,
大きな背中 追いかけてた あの憧れも
that yearning of chasing after that great back,
何千何万回と 生まれ変わっても
even if reborn thousands and tens of thousands of times,
何度も 何度も
again and again, again and again,
走り続けるよ
I'll keep on running!
覚ませ本能を 起こせ感動を
Awaken your instinct! Rouse the emotion!
刻め伝説を 叫べ Brave heart!
Engrave the legend! Shout out, Brave heart!
Whoa-oh-oh... Break! Break! Break out!
敗れて悔しゅうと 悔しくないのか
Don't you feel frustrated when defeated?
錆びてく 期待を前に 狼狽えたのか
Did you fluster before rusting expectations?
あれだけ切り拓き 満たしてきたんだ
We've paved the way and fulfilled this much,
目を覚ませ 歴史を塗り替えてやるさ
wake up! We're gonna rewrite history!
どんどん上がってく
Rising up more and more!
歓声巻き起こして Hit!
Stir up the cheers and Hit!
だんだん迫ってく
Approaching closer and closer!
あと少し 鬩ぎ合うシンパシー
Just a little more, competing sympathy!
(Fire!) 挑みたい
(Fire!) I want to challenge!
(Fight on!) 掴みたい
(Fight on!) I want to grasp it!
(Fight on!) 挑みたい
(Fight on!) I want to challenge!
掴みたい
I want to seize it!
(Fight on!) 刻みたい
(Fight on!) I want to carve it in!
伝えたい
I want to share it!
革命の火蓋切って
Spark the fire of revolution,
伝説の旗掲げてゆこう
and hoist the banner of legend!
さぁ Legend-Changer ロックに飛び込んで
Now, Legend-Changer, dive in rock style!
熱狂起こす当事者になれ
Become the ones who spark the frenzy!
Legend-Changer 大胆に行こうぜ
Legend-Changer, let's go boldly!
本能醒ませ
Awaken your instinct!
感動起こせ
Stir the thrill!
伝説刻んで
Etch the legend!
大地蹴って蹴って蹴って break!!
Stomp the ground, stomp, stomp, break!!
長い長い、夢の旅路を
Along this long, long dream journey,
今また一歩と確実に進んでいく。
I take yet another steady step forward.
鋭い眼差しで見据える先に、みんなの笑顔があると信じて。
Believing that beyond my sharp gaze, everyone's smiles await.
さぁ行け！
Now, go!
高嶺ルイ！
Takane Lui!
無数の足跡に見る栄冠を 憧れにして終わらせるな
Don't let the crown seen in countless footsteps end as mere admiration!
託された夢が堰を切って
The entrusted dreams burst through the floodgates,
今 私の闘志へと変わってゆく
and now turn into my fighting spirit!
さぁ Legend-Changer ロックに飛び込んで
Now, Legend-Changer, dive in rock style!
熱狂起こす当事者になれ
Become the ones who spark the frenzy!
Legend-Changer 大胆に行こうぜ
Legend-Changer, let's go boldly!
本能醒ませ
Awaken your instinct!
感動起こせ
Stir the thrill!
伝説刻んで
Etch the legend!
大地蹴って蹴って蹴って break!!
Stomp the ground, stomp, stomp, break!!
Wo-o-o Wo-o-o
Break break break out!!
もう救えない スクラブばかりのブルペンじゃ
There's no saving it in a bullpen full of scrubs.
ちゃちな青春も お涙も それすらないもんな
Cheap youth and tears—there's not even any of that.
相当に笑えない コメディのワンシーンもままならない
It's seriously unamusing, can't even manage a single comedy scene.
冷めたチャウダーを ただ混ぜ合わせた さもそんな人生さ
Just stirring cold chowder together, that's exactly what life is like.
掛け違えたボタンの身なりを いつのいつまで見ぬ振りしようか
How long should I pretend not to see my misbuttoned clothes?
そうかい 抗弁のしようもないな
Is that so? There's no point in arguing.
たまたま火事場に逃げ込んで 善かれと油を放り込んで
Happened to flee into a fire, threw in oil thinking it'd help,
生活も 計画も 全部がpotatoになっていく
and my daily life and my plans are all turning to mush like potato.
ぐつぐつ明日が泡吹いて 白目のままに茹で上がって
Tomorrow bubbles and foams away, boiling up while eyes roll back,
将来像 成功法 全部がpotatoになっていく
future vision, paths to success, all turning into mashed potato.
このままみんなで浸り散らかして どろどろに未来を溶かして
Let's all just soak in it as is, melting our future into mush,
そんな暮らしのままでKUSHA KUSHAになっていこうぜ
and keep living like this, getting all crumpled up!
もう時間がない 我等に見下す権利などない
There's no time left, we have no right to look down on anyone.
有象無象が発した ブーイングも 今なら勲章さ
Even the boos from the rabble are medals of honor to us now.
相当に笑えない 誰だってそう言わざるを得ない
It's seriously unamusing, anyone would have to agree.
バカの一つ覚えのように 空回って ただバターになっている
Spinning our wheels like a one-trick fool, just churning into butter.
始めはこんなつもりじゃなかった 誰か信じてくれやしないか
I didn't mean for it to be like this at first—won't somebody believe me?
一切、反証の余地はないが
Though there's absolutely no room for rebuttal...
あたかも何も知らぬ顔で ここぞと薪を投げ込んで
With an innocent look, throwing firewood onto the fire,
生活も 計画も 全部がpotatoになっていく
my daily life and my plans are all turning to mush like potato.
こんがり明日が煮え切って 姿見えぬほど燃え上がって
Tomorrow is cooked to a crisp, burning up until it's out of sight,
将来像 成功法 全部がpotatoになっていく
future vision, paths to success, all turning into mashed potato.
このままみんなで浸り散らかして どろどろに未来を溶かして
Let's all just soak in it as is, melting our future into mush,
そんなボウルの中で憂さ晴らしだとしようぜ
and let's call it blowing off steam inside such a bowl!
そんな暮らしのままでKUSHA KUSHAになっていこうぜ
Let's keep living like this, getting all crumpled up!
Welcome to the Wonderland
Welcome to Wonderland,
ここでは誰もが淫ら
everyone here is tainted.
How are you doing, miss?
But you're tempted by the moonlight
どうせ足掻いても無駄
no matter how you struggle, it's useless:
死ぬまで帰れない
you can't go home until you die.
不気味な猫が
An eerie cat
黒の中で笑う
smiles in the darkness:
「こんなにも濡れてるじゃないか」
"Aren't you soaking wet like this?"
官能へ響く声に そっと耳を立てて
Softly pricking up your ears to that voice echoing into sensuality,
まるでアリスのように――
just like Alice...
殺さぬように
So as not to kill,
生かさぬように
so as not to let live,
壊れるまで愛してあげる
I'll love you until you break.
快楽は媚薬なの
Pleasure is an aphrodisiac;
どんな兵もやけに
every single soldier
犬のように跪くわ
prostrates themselves like a dog.
This love is so insane
「そう、ここは夢の中
"Yes, this is inside a dream,
童話の魔女が出てきて光景」
a scene where a fairy-tale witch appears."
Birthdayでもないのにごちそう
A feast even though it's not a birthday,
優しい仮面もすり落ちそうで
and the gentle mask looks ready to slip off.
「ねえ、いつものママはどこ？」
"Hey, where is the usual Mama?"
それも気づかずに
Without even realizing that,
If I am dreaming
Somebody wake me up
Off with their heads!
そしてマリアンは走り
And then Mary Anne ran,
帽子屋がまたからからとうたう
as the Hatter sings rattlingly once more.
誰も皆 嘘で嘘を塗りつぶすとき
When everyone paints over lies with more lies,
「仮面の裏」がみえる
"what lies behind the mask" is revealed.
犯さぬように
So as not to violate,
汚さぬように
so as not to defile,
色欲を咲かす花園
a garden where lust blossoms.
この蜜が欲しいなら
If you want this nectar,
膝をつき血を舐め愛をのべ
get on your knees, lick the blood, and declare your love.
さあ心臓を捧げてちょうだい
Now, dedicate your heart to me.
Yes, your majesty
I cut out my heart for you
殺さぬように
So as not to kill,
生かさぬように
so as not to let live,
この狂気のディナーさえ
as I savor even this dinner of madness,
味わうほど あたしは――
I am...
The Queen of Hearts
さようなら 甘い街 私をくれた人
Goodbye, sweet town; the person who gave me life.
泣き癖 笑い映えに いくつの名残惜し
A habit of crying, shining in smiles; so many lingering regrets.
曖昧 未完成の あやまち 悟ったけど
Vague, incomplete mistakes—I realized them, but...
それでは 恋の季節 きらめきは戻らない
Even so, the season of love and its sparkle will never return.
シナリオ通りのカルマ
A karma playing out according to scenario,
飛び越えてきた人生
a life spent leaping over it all.
望みがなくなって
Now that all hope is gone,
空いた手のひらの手の
the empty palm of my hand...
それぞれの思惑 振りかざしても
Even if we brandish our separate intentions,
倒れない二人で立っていようね
let's stand together without falling.
派手でいてね そのままでいてね
Stay glamorous, stay just the way you are,
消えない幻
an unfading phantom.
夢幻クライマックス 最後の夜
Dream climax, on this final night,
エンドレスを刻め
etch eternity into time.
邪心に抱きしめても 壊れないくらい
Even if embraced with wicked intent,
強くなりすぎたから
we've grown far too strong to break.
あなたはわかんない
You'd never understand
抱える殻の孤独
the isolation within the shell I carry.
それでも無神経に
Even so, heedlessly,
季節が巡っていく
the seasons keep passing by.
いつも褒めてくれた 叱ってくれた
You always praised me, scolded me...
近所のおじさんの死 寂しくなるね
The passing of the old man next door leaves an ache of loneliness.
忘れないでいてね 憧れていてね
Please don't forget me, keep admiring me,
朽ちない面影
an undying memory.
だから無慈悲に 時を越えて
That's why ruthlessly, transcending time,
同じ地球 踏んでられるわ
we can walk upon this same earth.
魂だけ そばにおいてね
Just keep your soul by my side,
強く生きていけるの
and I can live on strong.
夢幻クライマックス 最後の夜
Dream climax, on this final night,
エンドレスを刻め
etch eternity into time.
邪心に抱きしめても 壊れないくらい
Even if embraced with wicked intent,
強くなりすぎた
we've grown far too strong to break.
寂しい
It's so lonely...
だから無慈悲に 時を越えて
That's why ruthlessly, transcending time,
同じ地球 踏んでられるわ
we can walk upon this same earth.
魂だけ そばにおいてね
Just keep your soul by my side,
強く生きていこうね
and let's live on strong together.
はい、ということで！ゲストパートを見ていただきました。いかがだったでしょうかー？いやー...
All right, everyone! You just watched the guest segment, how did you like it? Man...
本当にね、あの、ゲストの人とこういうことやりたい！っていうのを実現させていただきましたー！
I was truly able to bring to life all the things I've wanted to do with my guests!
皆さん、出演ありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much for joining me!
はい。詳しくはですね、明日の振り返り配信で、いろいろ裏話だったりとかをお話しさせていただこうかなと思いますので、
As for the details, I'll be sharing various behind-the-scenes stories during tomorrow's recap stream,
ぜひ振り返り配信も来てください！
so please come check out the recap stream as well!
そして！いかがですか？新衣装はー！
And! How do you like my new outfit?!
いかがでしょうかー？可愛いでしょうー？
How is it? Cute, isn't it?
たくさん、あの差分があったんですけど気づきましたか？
There were so many variations, did you notice them?
まあ、気づきますよね！
Well, of course you did!
最初は白い衣装から始まりまして、そして「うまぴょい伝説」ではですね、
We started off in the white outfit, and then during "Umapyoi Densetsu,"
あの、黒いパンツ姿で階段から、あそこの階段から登場したんですけれども、
I came out from the stairs over there wearing the black pants,
最初、みんな「え？ルイどこ？」みたいな感じになってて面白かったんですけど、
and it was hilarious how at first everyone was like, "Wait, where's Lui?"
なんかね、ウマ娘を知ってる人は、「まあ、あそこから来るんやろうな」って、
But people who know Umamusume were like, "Well, she's probably coming from over there,"
なんか後方腕組みしてたのがまた面白かったですね。
watching like smug veterans with arms crossed, which was so funny.
はい。えー、この後ですね、21時20分から、メン限で撮影会もございますので、
Also, after this, starting at 21:20, we'll have a members-only photoshoot stream,
そちらもぜひ、いろんな差分を見せていきたいなと思いますので、撮影会もぜひ来ていただけたら嬉しいでございます！
where I'd love to show you all the different outfit variations, so I'd be so happy if you could join!
はい！えー、重大発表はですね、あと2曲あるんですけど、
Yes! As for the major announcement, there are two songs left,
今から歌う曲の後で発表させていただきますので、
and I will be making the announcement after the next song,
ぜひ皆さん、ちょっと心待ちにしていただけたらなと思います！
so please look forward to it, everyone!
はい！じゃあ次の曲はですね、鷹嶺ルイ 2ndアルバム『ラピスラズリ』から1曲歌わせていただきます。
All right! For the next song, I'll be performing a track from Takane Lui's 2nd album, "Lapis Lazuli."
『抗う君への鎮魂歌』です。お願いします。
It's "Requiem for You Who Resist." Please enjoy.
抗う君への鎮魂歌
[Requiem for You Who Resist]
正しさだけ纏える術があれば
If there were a way to cloak myself in righteousness alone,
少しは救われるだろうか
would that bring me some salvation?
その瞳へと問いかける
I question those eyes of yours.
守るべきを捨てるべきと 誰かに惑わされて
Duped by someone into discarding what should be protected,
もう 心通わないなら
if our hearts no longer connect,
それは虚構です
then that is merely an illusion.
何も捨てずに
Without casting anything aside,
仇花 散ら無き猛者
like unfading warriors, like fruitless blossoms—
その覚悟で 幾星霜に
with that resolve, throughout countless ages,
正しさなどない
there is no such thing as righteousness.
失えば失うほどにさらに気高く
The more you lose, the more noble you become.
その意志で世界を恨め
With that will, curse this world.
心がきしんで 何度引き裂かれようと
Even if your heart creaks and is torn apart again and again,
抗え
fight back!
か弱き独りを守り抜くための
To protect this frail, solitary soul to the end,
この掌がどれだけ汚れてしまっても
no matter how stained these palms may become,
構わないさ
I don't care at all.
君が笑うなら
As long as you can smile,
僕は形にでもなる
I will become anything.
あさましき期待 悦らうだけなら
If all you do is indulge in wretched expectations,
人も獣も何ひとつ変わらない
humans and beasts are not different at all.
鎖に似た自由を嘆いては
Lamenting over a freedom that resembles chains,
歪に果てるのでしょう
you will surely meet a distorted end.
どうか君だけは
Please, if only you...
僕を覚えていてほしい
I just want you to remember me.
狂おしき未来を 慈雨へと誘う
Inviting this maddening future into a blessed rain...
俯けば俯くほどにさらに気高く
The more you cast your gaze down, the more noble you become.
その意志で世界を揺らせ
With that will, shake the world.
心が歪んで 何もかもが崩れても
Even if your heart twists and everything crumbles,
抗え
fight back!
か弱き独りを守り抜くための
To protect this frail, solitary soul to the end,
この掌がどれだけ汚れてしまっても
no matter how stained these palms may become,
構わないさ
I don't care at all.
君が笑うなら
As long as you can smile...
壊してみせる
I'll tear it all apart.
心から君が笑えたとき
When you can smile from the bottom of your heart,
僕は何処へゆくのだろう
where will I end up going?
不安も、否定も、葛藤も。
[Anxiety, denial, conflict.]
私が歌で「反逆」する。
[I will "rebel" through song.]
1st Live 開催決定
[1st Live Confirmed]
venue Kanadevia Hall
REBELLION Takane Lui 1st Live
[REBELLION - Takane Lui 1st Live]
ここから始まる。私だけの物語。
[It begins here. A story that is mine alone.]
はい！ということで！
Alright! And so!
私、鷹嶺ルイの初めてのソロライブが決定しました！イェーイ！
My very first solo live concert has been confirmed! Yay!
ということで、日程は半年後になる、なるのですが、
And so, the date will be in half a year...
半年後の2026年12月16日水曜日となっております！
It is scheduled for Wednesday, December 16, 2026, half a year from now!
会場はカナデビアホールです！
The venue is Kanadevia Hall!
もうね、4月の末にholoXライブがありまして、
At the end of April, we have the holoX Live,
そして9月にねぽっくすがありまして、
and in September, we have NePox,
そして12月に鷹嶺ルイのソロライブがあるということで、
and then in December is Takane Lui's solo live...
1年ね、2026年はすごい楽しめる年なんじゃないですか、ルイトモさん？
So isn't 2026 going to be an incredibly fun year, Louis-tomo?
はい。
Yes!
ということで、ルイトモさんにはね、色々お話ししたことがあると思うんですけれども、
So, I think I've mentioned this to you Louis-tomo before,
私は前々からですね、今まで音楽活動で道を作ってきてくれた先輩、
but for a long time, looking at the senpais who paved the way through music,
そら先輩だったり、すいちゃん、あずちゃん、そしてわためぇ、そしてカリ先輩のようにですね、
like Sora-senpai, Sui-chan, Azu-chan, Watame, and Calli-senpai,
ファーストライブから少しずつ段階、階段を上がっていって、
stepping up gradually from a 1st live, climbing up the stairs,
広い会場でソロライブをするという、そんな物語に憧れていました。
and eventually performing solo lives at large venues—I've always admired that journey.
だから、もし私がライブをやることになった際には、
That's why I felt that if I were ever to hold solo lives,
1st、2nd、3rd、4thと、
1st, 2nd, 3rd, 4th...
順々に会場を大きくして、ゆくゆくはアリーナという夢を叶えたい。
I wanted to expand the venue step by step and eventually reach an arena.
はい、そう思っていて、ルイトモさんにはつねづねお伝えをしていたと思います。
Yes, that was my wish, and I've always shared that with you all.
そのためにね、定期的なソロライブができる活動を頑張りたいなと思って、今まで努力をしてきました。
To make that happen, I've worked hard to sustain activities allowing regular solo lives.
そして、これからもします！はい。
And I'll keep giving it my all! Yes.
最近のホロライブはですね、結構より多くの方が入る会場での開催が多くて、
Lately in Hololive, concerts are often held at much larger venues,
私の夢はちょっと難しいのかなとは思っていたんですけれども、
so I wondered if my specific dream might be difficult,
こうやって私の夢を理解してくださり、叶えるべく、
but everyone understood my dream, and to help make it a reality,
まずは私の希望だったKanadevia Hallにてファーストライブをやらせていただくことになりました！
I've been given the opportunity to hold my 1st live at Kanadevia Hall, just as I wished!
おめでとう！ありがとう！
Congratulations! Thank you!
そして、あのトレンドもありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。
And thank you so much for getting it trending on X, too!
ここからが鷹嶺ルイの新章の物語の始まりでございます。
From here on marks the start of a brand-new chapter for Takane Lui.
まずはファーストライブを開催してから次を考えるべきだとは思うんですけれども、
I know I should probably hold the 1st live first before thinking about what's next,
私は、2nd、3rd、4th、その先のライブへのビジョンまで考えております！
but I'm already envisioning the 2nd, 3rd, 4th, and all the lives beyond!
今回の生誕ライブのタイトルでもあるように「LUMINOUS STAIRS」、輝かしい階段を駆け上がるために、
Just like the title of today's birthday live, "LUMINOUS STAIRS," in order to run up those radiant stairs,
そして、一緒にこの物語を紡いでいくために、
and to weave this story together with everyone,
少しでも行きたいなと思ってくださった方は、次に繋げるために応募したり、ライブを見てくれると嬉しいです！
if you'd like to come, please apply or tune into the live to help pave the way to the next stage!
ライブのタイトルは「REBELLION」になっております！
The title of the live concert is "REBELLION"!
はい、REBELLIONです。
Yes, REBELLION.
反逆という意味でございます。
It means "rebellion."
私がいつも抱えてる不安や、色々な否定の声、そして私自身の葛藤、
The anxiety I always carry, various voices of denial, and my own internal conflicts...
これからも私はそれを私の歌で反逆していきたい、
Going forward, I want to rebel against all of that through my songs.
そんな気持ちを込めてつけさせていただきました！
With those feelings in mind, that's what I named it!
最高のライブになるようにたくさん準備をしていますので、
I'm preparing a lot to make it the absolute best live show,
ぜひ楽しみに待っていてくださーい！
so please look forward to it!
ここからまた新たに鷹嶺ルイの物語が始まるということで、
With Takane Lui's new story beginning from here,
アーティスト写真を作りました！こちらです！
we created a new artist photo! Here it is!
はい、めちゃくちゃかっこいいですね。かっこ可愛い。
Yes! It looks super cool, doesn't it? Cool and cute.
アーティスト活動の際にはこちら使っていこうかなと思っておりますので、よろしくお願いいたします。
I'll be using this for my artist activities, so please look out for it!
そして、ここまで1st、2nd、アコースティックとアルバムを作ってきましたが、
Up until now, I've released my 1st, 2nd, and Acoustic albums,
今回、ライブを盛り上げるために4曲、新しく作りまして、
and this time, to hype up the live concert, we made 4 new tracks,
収録させていただいたミニアルバムも、本日ライブ終了後に予約開始でーす！
and pre-orders for this newly recorded mini-album start right after today's live!
ね、たくさん曲がありますね、鷹嶺ルイ。
Takane Lui sure has a lot of songs, huh?
『The LEGENDARY』というタイトルをつけさせていただきましたミニアルバムでございます。
This is the mini-album, titled "The LEGENDARY"!
この後に披露する新曲も入っております。
It also includes the new song I'll be performing after this.
完全生産限定盤には全員にサインが付きます！はい。
And the Limited Complete Edition comes with a signature for everyone! Yes.
完全生産限定盤には全員に直筆サインが付きますので、
Everyone who gets the Limited Complete Edition will receive a handwritten signature,
日頃の感謝を込めてサインを書きますので、ぜひ予約してください。
so please pre-order it! I'll be signing each one with gratitude.
お求めやすい通常盤もあります。こちらはちょっとサインついてないんですけど、
There's also an affordable Standard Edition. It doesn't include a signature, though.
通常盤もございますので、ぜひお手元に取っていただけますと嬉しいです。
Yes, the Standard Edition is also available, so I'd love it if you picked it up!
今回のライブ、そしてこの後に予約開始されるミニアルバムのハッシュタグは共通で「#鷹嶺ルイの反逆」となっております！
The official hashtag for both the live and the upcoming mini-album is "#鷹嶺ルイの反逆"!
皆さんたくさんポストして盛り上げてくださいね。ビジュ良いっしょ？ビジュ良いよね？
Please post a lot and hype things up, okay? The visual looks great, right? It really does!
以上、ソロライブとミニアルバムの告知でした。
That wraps up the solo live and mini-album announcements.
まだお知らせはございます！
There are still more announcements!
お知らせと重大告知がございます。次はお待ちかねのグッズ紹介です！
We have another announcement and a major notice. Next is the merch reveal!
はい、こちら！鷹嶺ルイ誕生日記念2026ということで、
Here it is! Takane Lui Birthday Celebration 2026!
えーキービジュアルはですね、
For the key visual...
今回お披露目させていただいた新衣装を着て、ケーキを食べている鷹嶺ルイです。
...it's Takane Lui wearing the newly unveiled outfit and eating cake.
久乃のらり先生に写真を撮っていただきました。可愛いでしょー？
Hisano Norari-sensei illustrated it for us. Isn't it cute?
それでは1つずつ見ていきましょう！
Well then, let's take a look at each item!
はい！1つ目はこちら、アクリルジオラマスタンドになっております。
Alright! First up is this acrylic diorama stand.
キービジュアルを使用したアクリルジオラマになっております。
It's an acrylic diorama featuring the key visual.
ルイ友さんとですね、がんもも可愛く執事風におめかしをしてます。可愛い。
Both Louis-tomo and Ganmo are cutely dressed up in butler style. So cute!
はい、続いてはこちら！はい！
Alright, next up is this!
新衣装にね、こっちだ、新衣装の、はい、こちらとかについている、
These are... over here, attached to my new outfit...
2種類のエムブレムをモチーフにしたピンバッジでございます。
...pin badges modeled after the two types of emblems!
色んなところにつけて密かにルイ友アピールをしてください。おしゃれでしょー？
Put them on various things and subtly show you're a Louis-tomo. Stylish, right?
はい、続いてはこちら！
Alright, next up is this!
はい！新衣装をモチーフにしたポーチになってます。おしゃれ！
It's a pouch themed after the new outfit. Stylish!
裏面はですね、メッシュポケットになっているので、
The back side has a mesh pocket,
缶バッジはもちろん、今回一緒に販売するピンバッジも付けやすいデザインになっております。
so it's designed to easily attach can badges or the pin badges releasing alongside it.
最後は、これ欲しかったんじゃないかな？こちら！
And finally, I bet you wanted this one... here it is!
はい！新衣装のショートパンツバージョンのホロフレと同じくらいのサイズのぬいぐるみです！可愛い！
It's a plushie in the shorts version of the new outfit, sized just like holoFriends! Cute!
ぜひこの機会にお迎えしていただけたら嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします。
I'd be so happy if you welcomed her home on this occasion! Please check it out.
フルセット購入特典はこちら！
Here is the bonus for purchasing the full set!
はい！ポストカードになっておりまして、数量限定版と通常版がございます。
Yes! It's a postcard, available in both limited quantity and standard editions.
数量限定版は、直筆サインが付きます。
The limited edition comes with a hand-written autograph.
たくさん用意しておるので、ゆっくり選んでください。
We've prepared plenty, so please take your time deciding.
販売時間はですね、少し余裕を持たせて21時15分からカートオープンです！
Giving a bit of leeway, sales will open at 21:15!
はい！以上、グッズ紹介でしたー！
That wraps up the merchandise introduction!
そして、もう1つ！重大告知です！こちら！
And one more thing! A major announcement! Look here!
なんと！私が夢見ていました、BAYFM78さんにてレギュラーラジオの番組が決定しましたー！！
Amazingly, a regular radio show on BAYFM78 that I've always dreamed of has been decided!
放送日はですね、毎週金曜日24時30分から24時57分、
The broadcast will be every Friday from 24:30 to 24:57,
初回放送日は7月3日金曜日となっておりますー！
and the first broadcast is on Friday, July 3rd!
Xでも初回配信用の、お便りを募集するので、メールアドレスも公開しますので、
We'll be soliciting fan mail for the first show on X and sharing the email address,
Xのフォローをよろしくお願いいたします！楽しみに待っててねー！
so please follow my X account! Look forward to it!
はい！次の曲が最後の曲になります。先ほども紹介させていただきました新曲になっておりまして、名前は『Soar』と言います。
Alright! The next song will be the last one. It's the new song I introduced earlier, titled "Soar".
はい！ソロライブでもみんなと一緒に歌いたいなと思って、みんなが声出しできる新曲を作ってきましたー！
Wanting to sing together with everyone at my solo concert, I made a new song you can shout along to!
ナナホシ管弦楽団さんに書き下ろしていただいた爽やかな楽曲になっております。
It's a refreshing track written for me by Nanahoshi Orchestra.
この後21時から、21時ちょっと過ぎかもしれないけど、ミュージックビデオのプレミア公開もあります！
After this, from 21:00—or maybe a little after—there'll be a Music Video premiere!
はい！楽曲は本日24時にリリースです！
Yes! The song will be released tonight at 24:00!
この曲はですね、コーラスはホロメンが歌ってくれております。
For this song, the chorus vocals were provided by Holo members!
ライブまでにたくさん聴いて覚えてくれたら嬉しいです。
I'd be so glad if you listened a lot and memorized it before the live concert!
では、早速聴いていただきましょう！
Then, let's have you listen right away!
はい！皆さんと一緒に歌いたい曲、『Soar』です。どうぞ！
The song I want to sing with everyone, "Soar". Please enjoy!
何度でも君を呼んで また歩いてゆく
No matter how many times, I'll call your name and keep walking on
Woah-oh-oh-oh...
一歩 踏み出したらもう未来さ
Just taking one step forward is already the future
昨日 つまずいた道も 今日からは近道だ
Even the path I stumbled on yesterday is a shortcut from today on
息をするたびに広がる景色
The scenery expanding every time I take a breath
私を信じていいと言って
Tell me that it's okay to believe in myself
つぶやきも希望になって あふれては声になって
Even murmurs turn into hope, overflowing into a voice
何度 目を閉じても 消せないな
No matter how many times I close my eyes, I can't erase it
高く飛べるよ そうだろう 抑えられない
We can fly high, right? I can't hold it back
羽ばたく理由を誰かに許されなくても
Even if no one gives me permission to spread my wings
もう決めたよ 迷わない
I've already decided, I won't hesitate
向かい風も きっと進んでる証拠だって
Even a headwind is surely proof that we're moving forward
君に伝えるんだ
I'm going to convey it to you!
Woah-oh-oh-oh...
どんな重力も 心までは 縛れない 曲げられない
No amount of gravity can ever bind or bend my heart
この手で確かめたい
I want to make sure with my own hands
胸 焦がした思いで
With feelings that burned my chest
爪痕をさぁ刻んで 嵐の空模様 切り裂いて
Let's carve our claw marks and tear through the stormy sky!
もっと輝くよ そうだろう
I will shine even brighter, isn't that right?
叫べばいい
Just shout it out.
憧れより眩しい唄
A song brighter than yearning,
そして激しい唄
and a fierce song.
いつか耳を塞いだ
Once, I covered my ears,
その両手が
but those two hands...
きっと翼になる
...will surely become wings.
そう思うんだ
That's what I believe.
ゆずれない衝動
An unyielding urge...
高く飛べるよ そうだろう
I can fly high, isn't that right?
抑えられない
Uncontainable,
羽ばたく理由を
even if no one...
誰かに許されなくても
...gives me permission to spread my wings.
もう決めたよ 迷わない
I've already decided, I won't hesitate.
向かい風も きっと進んでる
Even head winds are proof...
証拠だって
...that I'm moving forward.
君に伝えるんだ
I will convey it to you.
何度でも君を呼んで
Calling your name again and again,
また歩いてゆく
I will walk on once more.
皆さん 本日は生誕祭に来てくださってありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming to my birthday celebration today!
ソロライブ楽しみにしててねー！
Look forward to my solo concert!
ばいばーい！
Bye-bye!
[手紙] ルイ友へ
みんなの応援のおかげで… ついに私もソロライブできるよっ!!
[Letter] To Rui-tomo:
Thanks to everyone's support, I'm finally getting my own solo concert!!
本当にありがとう♡
もっともっと磨かれて光り輝く階段をのぼって、いろんな景色をみせてね
Thank you so much! ♡
As I keep polishing myself and climbing the shining stairs, please show me all kinds of scenery.
(任せろー!!)
私の物語には君が必要です!!
("Leave it to us!!")
I need you in my story!!
これからもよろしくネ!!
るい 2026.06.11
Please stay by my side from now on too!!
— Rui, 2026.06.11